Ayomide Ibosiola

Technical Recruiter || Software Developer



https://ayomideibosiola.netlify.app,https://calendly.com/ayomideibosiola

https://linkedin.com/in/ayomide-ibosiola

Summary

Data-driven Technical Recruiter capable of Advanced Boolean Search to identify and mine top candidates with a strong Software Development background; specialized in building web and mobile applications that are aesthetically pleasing and logic-driven.

There's nothing like the thrill of a candidate's enthusiastic "Yes!" to an offer, and an equally pleased Hiring Manager who just landed a top performer. Perhaps even more satisfying is successfully recruiting a superstar and then seeing him/her develop a billion-dollar product. Knowing my efforts impact the bottom line keeps me going every day.

In addition to my knowledge base, I actively seek out new technologies and stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements, currently building experience in Designing HR Processes, TechnicalRecruiting, Talent Sourcing, Strategy Development, Recruitment and Selection, Employee on-boarding, Payroll Management, HRIS, Employer branding, Learning and development, and other Human Resources functions spanning Tech Start-ups, Consulting, Financial technology space, and NGO sectors.

This has allowed me to stay ahead of the curve and deliver exceptional work to all of my clients.

Education

Apr 2015 - Apr 2019 BSc. Microbiology Obafemi Awolowo University, Ile-Ife

Employment

Apr 2022 - Present

Recruitment Consultant - Contract

VGS Recruitment Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria

Building relationships with clients.

Sourcing potential candidates on platforms such as LinkedIn, and GitHub. Serving as an ambassador for VGS Recruitment Solutions and representing her in

potential candidates' first interactions with the organization.

Performing pre-screening calls to analyze applicants' abilities. Interviewing candidates combining various methods (e.g. structured interviews, technical assessments, and behavioral questions).

Coordinating with Technical team leaders to forecast department goals and hiring needs. Crafting and sending personalized recruiting emails with current job openings to passive candidates.

Keeping up-to-date with new technological trends and products.

Creating a seamless candidate experience through all stages.

Actively engaging and promoting diversity and inclusion in hiring strategies.

Apr 2022 - Present Community Leader || Senior Technical Recruiter - Volunteering Jobs Meet Devs, Lagos, Nigeria

Communicating mistakes software developers make every day in their job search pursuit with the heart of a Technical Recruiter and the mind of a Software Developer. Helping developers avoid the regular pitfalls in hiring processes by using any collection of materials including animate and inanimate objects and human and non-human resources useful in teaching and learning situations to help achieve desired learning objectives.

Sharing job opportunities for members of the community.

Creating systems for organizational growth.

Building an all-round development atmosphere.

March2020 - Present

Senior Recruitment Consultant (Tech) - Contract

Xapic Technologies, Lagos, Nigeria

Sourcing potential candidates on platforms such as LinkedIn and GitHub

Serving as an ambassador for Xapic Technologies and representing her in potential candidates' first interaction with the organization.

Performing pre-screening calls to analyze applicants' abilities.

Interviewing candidates combining various methods (e.g. structured interviews, technical assessments, and behavioral questions).

Coordinating with Technical team leaders to forecast department goals and hiring needs.

Crafting and sending personalized recruiting emails with current job openings to passive candidates.

Keeping up-to-date with new technological trends and products.

Creating a seamless candidate experience through all stages.

Actively engaging and promoting diversity and inclusion in hiring strategies.

Sep 2021 - Mar 2022

Frontend Developer | Technical Recruiter - Full-time

Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bengaluru, India

Pinpointed candidate motivators and used them to successfully recruit quality candidates.

Analyzed job descriptions and communicated with the Hiring Manager (Pericius Technologies Pvt. Ltd) to clarify terms that could be vague; earned job satisfaction rates of 95 percent from candidate/company matches as a result of this attention to detail.

Created new features, functionality, and capabilities, specifically in the Contract Management System using ReactJS, Ant Design, Material UI, and Java. Performed bug fixes and code reviews.

Recommended solutions for a streamlined, user-friendly interface with the design team.

Aug 2021 - Nov 2021 Technical Copywriter - Contract Marketpath Inc, Indianapolis, USA

Gathered and analyzed technical and product information from various sources to document new or changing product functionality.

Developed product manuals, how-to guides, website help sections, journal articles, and other content that distills technical information with ease and clarity.

May 2021 - Jun 2021 Frontend Developer - Contract Mezovest, Lagos, Nigeria

Built an online payment gateway that allows businesses to make and receive payments across continents, currencies, preferred payment methods, and platforms.

Oct 2020 - Jan 2021 Software Developer - Contract Royal Crystal Airways, Lagos, Nigeria

Built the Web Application for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip using ReactJS, Redux, jQuery, Vanilla JavaScript, Material-UI, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Stylus, and ES6.

Oversaw the outsourced Mobile Application development for Royal Crystal Airways and Royal Trip.

Jan 2019 - Mar 2020 Frontend Developer - Contract Midra Solutions, Lagos, Nigeria

Maintained, optimized, troubleshot, and improved websites.

Created standardized websites and mobile responsive applications using a mobile-first approach and strategy.

Implemented applications and landing pages from concept through deployment. Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments. Built reusable code for future use.

Jan 2017 - Jan 2019 Software Developer (Intern) - Full-time Lagosbuild, Lagos, Nigeria

Standardized website output with a new, responsive, mobile-first approach and strategy.

Assessed UX and UI designs for technical feasibility. Integrated data from various back-end services and databases.

Skills

ATS Recruitment Software Boolean search (LinkedIn and Google) X-ray search - Recruit'em Leadership People Management Employee Onboarding MS Office suite (Excel, Word, PowerPoint) Recruitment Selection Learning & Development

Vanilla JavaScript ReactJS Ant Design Bootstrap VueJS Material UI

Certificates

Mar 2022

Tech Recruitment Certified Professional - DevSkiller

Jan 2022 ReactJS for Beginners - Simplilearn

Jan 2022 JavaScript for Beginners - Simplilearn

Dec 2021 Getting Started with ReactJS Components - Simplilearn

Apr 2021 Soft Skills Course - Jobberman Nigeria

Mar 2021 Certificate of Language Ability - Emmersion

Mar 2021 HTML/CSS and JavaScript - TestDome